<resources>
    <string name="app_name" translatable="false">Space Race</string>
    <string name="app_id" translatable="false">444006907114</string>
    <!--<string name="server_client_id">444006907114-dh61m4sijhkqcaoufu7tqbo6o1rplqra.apps.googleusercontent.com</string>
-->

    <string name="slide1Title" translatable="false">Padova Space Week</string>

    <string name="slide2Title">Scavenger hunt</string>
    <string name="slide2Subtitle">Discover the right path finding hints and resolving riddles</string>

    <string name="slide3Title">Challenge your friends!</string>


    <string name="title_activity_room">RoomActivity</string>

    <string name="game_title">Button Clicker 2000!</string>
    <string name="game_blurb">A sample game that tests your ability to click a button. Can you click faster than your friends? Only one way to find out! To play this game with friends, you must sign in with Google.</string>
    <string name="single_player">Single Player</string>
    <string name="single_player_explanation">Get some practice!</string>
    <string name="quick_game">Quick game</string>
    <string name="invite_players">Invite friends</string>
    <string name="see_invitations">See invitations</string>
    <string name="quick_game_explanation">Challenge a random opponent.</string>
    <string name="invite_players_explanation">Invite friends to play a game.</string>
    <string name="see_invitations_explanation">See who is inviting you right now.</string>
    <string name="inv_popup_text">Incoming invitation!</string>
    <string name="accept_popup_invite">Accept</string>
    <string name="sign_out">Sign Out</string>
    <string name="please_wait">Please wait&#8230;</string>
    <string name="instructions">Click the button as fast as you can!</string>
    <string name="game_problem">An error occurred while starting the game. Please try again.</string>
    <string name="click_me">Click me!</string>
    <string name="is_inviting_you">is challenging you to a game!</string>
    <string name="signin_other_error">There was an issue with sign in. Please try again later.</string>

    <string name="gamehelper_sign_in_failed">Failed to sign in. Please check your network connection and try again.</string>
    <string name="gamehelper_app_misconfigured">The application is incorrectly configured. Check that the package name and signing certificate match the client ID created in Developer Console. Also, if the application is not yet published, check that the account you are trying to sign in with is listed as a tester account. See logs for more information.</string>
    <string name="gamehelper_license_failed">License check failed.</string>
    <string name="gamehelper_unknown_error">Unknown error.</string>

    <string name="sign_in_other_error">There was an issue with sign-in, please try again later.</string>
    <string name="sign_in_failed">Failed to sign in. Please check your network connection and try again.</string>
    <string name="app_misconfigured">The application is incorrectly configured. Check that the package name and signing certificate match the client ID created in Developer Console. Also, if the application is not yet published, check that the account you are trying to sign in with is listed as a tester account. See logs for more information.</string>
    <string name="license_failed">License check failed.</string>
    <string name="unknown_error">Unknown error.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_sign_in">SignInActivity</string>

    <!--main activity buttons-->
    <string name="new_match">Create new match</string>
    <string name="join_existing_match">Join existing match</string>
    <string name="high_scores">High scores</string>
    <string name="credits">Credits</string>
    <string name="title_activity_credits">CreditsActivity</string>

    <!--credits activity-->
    <string name="augugrumi_team" translatable="false">Augugrumi team</string>
    <string name="find_proj">You can find us on</string>
    <string name="creators" translatable="false">Davide Polonio\nFederico Tavella\nMarco Zanella</string>
    <string name="slide1Subtitle">Explore astronomy related places in Padova</string>
    <string name="slide3Subtitle">Sign In with Google, play and win!</string>
    <string name="warningSlider3Title">Login error</string>
    <string name="warningSlider3SubTitle">Something went wrong during the login</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map">MapActivity</string>

    <!--map activity-->
    <string name="permission_rationale">Location permission is needed for core functionality</string>
    <string name="permission_denied_explanation">Permission was denied, but is needed for core
        functionality.</string>
    <string name="settings">Settings</string>

    <!--schede-->
    <string name="introduction">Avete mai incontrato Galileo a Padova? E sapete che la   prima stella cometa “con la coda” fu dipinta proprio a Padova da Giotto, nella celebre Cappella degli Scrovegni? Storie di stelle e pianeti, orologi e meridiane si nascondono nelle città, sotto un portico, dentro a una chiesa, sulla facciata di un palazzo e ci raccontano quanto la conoscenza del cielo fosse importante per i nostri antenati. Il progetto “Seconda stella a destra” traccia un itinerario alla ricerca degli elementi celesti disseminati nel centro storico di Padova e permette di scoprire una città non convenzionale, tra astronomia, arte e cultura.    L’itinerario parte simbolicamente da Prato della Valle, ai piedi della statua di Galileo Galilei, che proprio a Padova fece delle scoperte che cambiarono profondamente la nostra conoscenza astronomica. Il percorso si snoda tra i luoghi del centro storico, dentro le mura, e si conclude alla Specola, sede dell’Osservatorio astronomico di INAF – Istituto Nazionale di Astrofisica. Vi porterà a scoprire i luoghi di Galileo, dalla sede dell’Università in cui insegnava alla sua casa, i luoghi del tempo, come meridiane e orologi, e i luoghi del cielo, raffigurazioni cioè di volte stellate, simboli celesti, stemmi.  Potrete seguire l’itinerario per intero, scegliere un’esplorazione tematica o, ancora, creare il vostro percorso, saltando qua e là. L’importante è che ricordiate una cosa: di alzare gli occhi al cielo!</string>
    <string name="card_1_prato_della_valle">Eyes toward the sky and arm pointing at something up there: have you ever met Galileo Galilei in Padua? You will find him in the spectacular Prato della Valle, where he appears as one of the 78 statues of illustrious people that decorate the largest square of the city (maybe the largest in Europe!). The “Prato”, that’s what the locals call this square, although it actually has a elliptical shape and a green island at the centre. It’s in an area reclaimed from a swamp, which was drained at the end of the Eighteenth century. It has always been a lively place and it still hosts a busy market every Saturday.</string>
    <string name="title_card_1">A date with Galileo</string>
    <string name="card_2_sant_antonio_basilica">For locals ”the Saint” is Saint Anthony: they’ll know who you mean. So universal and loved, he doesn’t even need to be named. Artists such as Giotto, Donatello, Mantegna and Giusto de’Menabuoi have all left their mark on “his” grand Basilica over the centuries. Its domes, its cloisters and its works of art reveal stories of devotion, spirituality and beauty. Inside you’ll find various starry vaults and outside a splendid sun on the entrance, a copy of the one by Mantegna, which you’ll find inside the Basilica. It’s an ancient symbol for divinity.</string>
    <string name="title_card_2">Where Mantegna’s Sun shines</string>
    <string name="card_3_galileo_house">Padua is the place where Galileo Galilei lived “the best eighteen years of my whole life”, teaching, studying and observing the sky. He lived in a street once called Borgo Vignali and later rechristened via Galileo Galilei. Apparently that’s the place where he discovered Jupiter’s satellites, a crucial moment in the birth of the modern scientific method. The house is not open to visitors, but there’s a plaque outside in memory of the scientist. For the rest, just free your imagination!</string>
    <string name="title_card_3"></string>
    <string name="card_4_chiesa_san_francesco">Almost hidden in a shadowy street, you will find this beautiful but neglected church, with 26 arches outside. Begun int he fifteenth century, it was once part of a great complex, including a convent, the first hospital in Padua, the charitable Scuola della Carità and the Oratorio di Santa Margherita. Inside the church, between an almost-secret garden and a canvas ascribed to Veronese, you will also find a plaque to Stella Stella, dedicated by his son.</string>
    <string name="title_card_4">The stars on</string>
    <string name="card_5_chiesa_santa_sofia">One of the oldest churches in town, Santa Sofia’s character comes from the contrast between the elegant external structure and the great sparseness of the interior. Its inclined façade can be intimidating, but it’s worth visiting the church because inside you will find other traces of Galileo’s presence. At the end of the nave is baptismal font where Vincenzo, the scientist’s third and last son, was christened.</string>
    <string name="title_card_5">On Galileo’s traces</string>
    <string name="card_6_borgo_altinate">In the past, this street was one of the main thoroughfares of Padua, because it was near the main town canals, which are now filled with soil. The history and cultural richness of the area are evident in the surviving aristocratic palaces, the Pollini conservatory and the Centro Culturale Altinate. Together, they create a lively atmosphere, in which it is pleasant to stroll up to the porta Altinate. Just before you get there, you might notice a curious six pointed ”star” represented on a shield. Some believe it is the symbol of an ancient urban district; others say it represents the wheel of a printing-press, in memory of the first family of publishers in town.</string>
    <string name="title_card_6">The sense of the stars</string>
    <string name="card_7_chiesa_eremitani">Known as the Chiesa degli Eremitani, the Church of the Hermits, because the old monastery attached to it (the current location of the Musei Civici) was a destination for pilgrims passing by. Reconstructed after being bombed in the Second World War, it contains the famous cappella Ovetari, frescoed by Andrea Mantegna, together with other frescos ascribed to Giusto de’ Menabuoi and parts of frescos by Guariento. In the lower left part of the chapel of the apse you will see allegorical decorations of the five planets known to to antiquity, together with the Sun and Moon. Can you identify them?</string>
    <string name="title_card_7">The face of the planets</string>
    <string name="card_8_cappella_scrovegni">A masterpiece of world art, the chapel was painted by Giotto between 1303 and 1305. It’s a cornucopia of charming visual inventions: a powerful place that almost overwhelms your eyes with the spiritual magic of its frescoes. These depict stories from the New and Old Testament, surmounted by the incredible blue ceiling dotted with stars. That’s where Giotto ‘invented’ the comet as a pictorial subject, representing it for the first time as a ball of fire, with its long tail upwards and the brilliance of the gold tempera painting filling it with light. The inspiration? Maybe Halley’s Comet, visible in the sky when Giotto was working.</string>
    <string name="title_card_8">Where Giotto invented the comet</string>
    <string name="card_9_caffè_pedrocchi">Opened in 1831, the Pedrocchi is Padua’s historical café. For years, it has been the meeting point for intellectuals, professors and students. Designed by Giuseppe Jappelli, it was originally open twenty-four hours a day, and that’s why it was known as the “café without doors”. It was at the centre of the upheavals of the Italian Risorgimento, and you can still find the hole made by an Austrian bullet during the riots. Among the various rooms of the upper floor, the Egyptian room reveals unusual attractions: a winged sun that decorates the architrave of the Egyptian-style façade and a splendid starry sky on the ceiling, maybe not Egyptian and only decorative… but it doesn’t matter, it’s still beautiful!</string>
    <string name="title_card_9">An Egyptian sky at the heart of town</string>
    <string name="card_10_orologio_civile">When the clock was built, civil time replaced the sun and the bells of the churches in marking out everyday activities. Its location was strategic: in the nerve centre for commercial exchanges, right next to the busiest squares crowded with people going about their everyday business, and just over from the cattle market and the place where you could rent carriages. Even today, it’s still a lively place, where you can take part in the noble art of the promenade so loved by locals, students and tourists.</string>
    <string name="title_card_10">The time of the town</string>
    <string name="card_11_galileo_university">Università di Padova was founded in 1222, and is one of the oldest and most prestigious in the world. Also known as the Bo, because it was once the location of the inn Hospitium Bovis, it has the head of a bull as a symbol. Entering the Cortile Antico, the ancient courtyard, you’ll find yourself surrounded by many coats of arms decorated by heraldic stars, in memory of illustrious students and professors. On the upper floors surrounding the courtyard, you will find the Great Hall, where Galileo gave his crowded lectures, and the Sala dei Quaranta, which preserves his chair. You can also visit the anatomical theater, the first example in the world of a permanent structure created to teach anatomy.</string>
    <string name="title_card_11">Galileo’s University</string>
    <string name="card_12_palazzo_ragione">Seat of the town court until 1797, the Palazzo della Ragione remains the centre of public and commercial life. It is also called the Salone, because the upper floor contain a hall with an enormous loggia, decorated with a cycle of great frescoes with astrological-astronomic subjects. The ground floor hosts a typical indoor market  and just outside, tables and chairs ideal if you need to take a break. Looking up, there it is: the sundial of Palazzo della Ragione, that once held a fundamental role in this commercial area.</string>
    <string name="title_card_12">Sundials and astronomical stories</string>
    <string name="card_13_santa_lucia">Today an elegant area of chic boutiques, the network of streets that goes from via San Fermo to Santa Lucia was once one of the most popular areas of the town. Walking around with your head in the clouds you can find comet stars with wavy tails, hidden on the vaults of the galleries and between ancient buildings. The most illustrious of these ancient palaces looks out onto via Marsilio. It’s the house of Ezzelino, tyrant of Padua in 1200.</string>
    <string name="title_card_13">Stars where you least expect them</string>
    <string name="card_14_oratorio_san_rocco">In via Santa Lucia, just next to the church, on an area originally set aside for a cemetery, you’ll find the Oratorio di San Rocco. Built between 1525 and 1542, it is a charming building of great beauty. Two frescoed rooms depicting Saint Rocco’s life. As you enjoy the wonder of the place, a canopy of stars will open before you.</string>
    <string name="title_card_14">A starry sky for a roof</string>
    <string name="card_15_piazza_signori">The square of the lords, so-called because the rulers of Padua, the Carraresi, lived there. It has now become the most elegant square of Padua. Its fifteenth-century elegance is framed by other prestigious buildings: the Loggia della Gran Guardia, the San Clemente church and, opposite, the palazzo del Capitanio and the Torre dell’Orologio. The latter, designed by Jacopo Dondi, is an astronomical and astrological clock, the first in Europe. It depicts the Sun, the Moon and the planets, all moving inside a band of sky containing by the Zodiac. Curiously, instead of the usual symbol for Libra, you will find the claws of a Scorpion instead. Is it the same scorpion you find hidden on a column of the square?</string>
    <string name="title_card_15">Dondi’s clock and the hidden scorpion</string>
    <string name="card_16_chiesa_san_nicolò">This corner of the town is a “secret” place, far from traffic and the crowd, enchanting and charming. On piazzetta San Nicolò sits the eponymous church, a miniature jewel, which contain frescoes, a great work of art and also a fragment of sky: the light blue canopy of stars coating the dress of the terracotta statue of the Virgin Mary, who holds the baby Jesus.</string>
    <string name="title_card_16">A canopy of stars</string>
    <string name="card_17_battistero_duomo">In the area right behind the Ghetto, the pavement in front of the Duomo becomes a “square” for children playing and students on a short break. It hosts the Romanesque baptistery frescoed by Giusto de’ Menabuoi with scenes from the Old and New Testament, the Apocalypse and the Paradise. Notice the panel representing the creation of the world, a fascinating example of how the sky and the Earth were depicted according to the astronomical and geographical knowledge of the time.</string>
    <string name="title_card_17">The creation of the Universe</string>
    <string name="card_18_piazza_capitaniato">Piazza Capitaniato is familiar and elegant. It seems to invite you to stop for a break among its trees, its bicycles, the coming and going of the students. An intimate but lively place, once occupied by the Reggia dei Carraresi, the lords of Padua. The Reggia, today represented only by Sala dei Giganti and the loggia (in via Accademia),  was a meeting point for intellectuals and artists, including Galileo, Petrarch and the painter Guariento. The Reggia later became the seat of the Accademia Galileiana: a prestigious institution, founded in 1599, which brought together University professors, artists and thinkers, like Galileo himself. Today, the academy is still dedicated to cultural activities.</string>
    <string name="title_card_18" translatable="false"></string>
    <string name="card_19_chiesa_san_pietro">Continuing your walk beyond the trees of piazza Capitaniato,  you will reach the borders of another Padua, quiet and ancient. Enjoy via Patriarcato, and follow it to the church of San Pietro, which is almost camouflaged between the palaces of the street that bears its name. Inside you will discover two starry skies: the first, inside the great dome above the altar, depicting the four evangelists; the second, intense and encircling, in the chapel dedicated to the Black Madonna of Loreto. The altar, depicting the four evangelists; the second, intense and encircling, in the chapel dedicated to the Black Madonna of Loreto.</string>
    <string name="title_card_19">The church with two skies</string>
    <string name="card_20_chiesa_san_tomaso">On Sant’Agostino bridge – which connects the riviera Paleocapa with piazza Castello – you will find this little-known church, which has a mysterious charm all of its own. If you have a look inside, you can see a gloomy sky, with a celestial object. The nature and meaning of this object remain uncertain even today.</string>
    <string name="title_card_20">The mysteriour sky</string>
    <string name="card_20_specola">The Specola appears framed by trees, water and sky, in a corner filled with silence and beauty. Originally the tower of the Carraresi castle and even before the place where the tyrant Ezzelino locked up and tortured his prisoners, in the eighteenth century it was converted to an observatory, becoming the astronomical specula. Today it is the headquarters of the National Institute of Astrophysics and of the Museo La Specola. Inside, you will discover a universe suspended in time, a maze of vaults, stairs and corridors in which to explore the work of astronomers.</string>
    <string name="title_card_21">The way to the stars</string>
    <string name="name_card_1" translatable="false">Prato della Valle</string>
    <string name="name_card_2">Sant’Antonio\'s Basilica - piazza del Santo 11</string>
    <string name="name_card_3">Galileo’s House - Via Galileo Galilei 17</string>
    <string name="name_card_4">San Francesco\'s church - via San Francesco 118</string>
    <string name="name_card_5">Santa Sofia\'s church - via Santa Sofia 102</string>
    <string name="name_card_6" translatable="false">Borgo Altinate</string>
    <string name="name_card_10">Civilian clock - via VIII Febbraio</string>
    <string name="name_card_7">Eremitani\'s church - piazza Eremitani 9</string>
    <string name="name_card_8">The Scrovegni\'s Cappella - piazza Eremitani 8</string>
    <string name="name_card_9" translatable="false">Caffè Pedrocchi - via VIII Febbraio 15</string>
    <string name="name_card_11">The Bo - via VIII Febbraio 2</string>
    <string name="name_card_12">Palace of Ragione - piazza delle Erbe</string>
    <string name="name_card_13">Toward Saint Lucia</string>
    <string name="name_card_14">Oratory of San Rocco - via Santa Lucia</string>
    <string name="name_card_15">Signori\' square - Piazza dei Signori</string>
    <string name="name_card_16">Saint Nicolò\'s church - piazzetta San Nicolò</string>
    <string name="name_card_17">The Baptistery of the Cathedral - piazza Duomo</string>
    <string name="name_card_18">Capitaniato square - Accademia galileiana</string>
    <string name="name_card_19">San Pietro\'s church - via San Pietro 125</string>
    <string name="name_card_20">San Tomaso\'s church - via San Tomaso 3</string>
    <string name="name_card_21" translatable="false">Specola - vicolo dell’Osservatorio 5</string>

    <!--hint fragment - place explanation view-->
    <string name="skip_quiz">&lt;&lt; Skip quiz</string>
    <string name="to_quiz">Quiz &gt;&gt;</string>

    <!--hint fragment - quizzes-->
    <string name="question_1">Question 1</string>
    <string name="question_2">Question 2</string>
    <string name="question_3">Question 3</string>

    <!--hint fragment - quiz result-->
    <string name="your_score">Your score is</string>
    <string name="to_next_hint">To next hint</string>

    <!--hint fragment - next hint-->
    <string name="next_hint">Next hint</string>

    <!--Preferences - maps-->
    <string name="map_style">Map style</string>
    <string name="map_style_summary">Choose the style of the map displayed</string>
    <string name="mars_map" translatable="false">Bloody mars</string>
    <string name="dark_moon_map" translatable="false">The dark side of the moon</string>
    <string name="light_moon_map" translatable="false">The light side of the moon</string>
    <string name="uranus" translatable="false">Uranus</string>

    <!--debug-->
    <string name="lorem_ipsum_short" translatable="false">Lorem ipsum</string>
    <string name="lorem_ipsum_medium" translatable="false">Sed ut perspiciatis unde omnis iste natus error sit voluptatem accusantium doloremque laudantium, totam rem aperiam eaque ipsa, quae ab illo inventore veritatis et quasi architecto beatae vitae dicta sunt, explicabo.</string>
    <string name="lorem_ipsum" translatable="false">Sed ut perspiciatis unde omnis iste natus error sit voluptatem accusantium doloremque laudantium, totam rem aperiam eaque ipsa, quae ab illo inventore veritatis et quasi architecto beatae vitae dicta sunt, explicabo. Nemo enim ipsam voluptatem, quia voluptas sit, aspernatur aut odit aut fugit, sed quia consequuntur magni dolores eos, qui ratione voluptatem sequi nesciunt, neque porro quisquam est, qui dolorem ipsum, quia dolor sit, amet, consectetur, adipisci velit, sed quia non numquam eius modi tempora incidunt, ut labore et dolore magnam aliquam quaerat voluptatem. Ut enim ad minima veniam, quis nostrum exercitationem ullam corporis suscipit laboriosam, nisi ut aliquid ex ea commodi consequatur? Quis autem vel eum iure reprehenderit, qui in ea voluptate velit esse, quam nihil molestiae consequatur, vel illum, qui dolorem eum fugiat, quo voluptas nulla pariatur? [33] At vero eos et accusamus et iusto odio dignissimos ducimus, qui blanditiis praesentium voluptatum deleniti atque corrupti, quos dolores et quas molestias excepturi sint, obcaecati cupiditate non provident, similique sunt in culpa, qui officia deserunt mollitia animi, id est laborum et dolorum fuga. Et harum quidem rerum facilis est et expedita distinctio. Nam libero tempore, cum soluta nobis est eligendi optio, cumque nihil impedit, quo minus id, quod maxime placeat, facere possimus, omnis voluptas assumenda est, omnis dolor repellendus. Temporibus autem quibusdam et aut officiis debitis aut rerum necessitatibus saepe eveniet, ut et voluptates repudiandae sint et molestiae non recusandae. Itaque earum rerum hic tenetur a sapiente delectus, ut aut reiciendis voluptatibus maiores alias consequatur aut perferendis doloribus asperiores repellat.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_starting">StartingActivity</string>

    <string name="leaderboard_id" translatable="false">CgkI6vn-hvYMEAIQAQ</string>
</resources>
